Henry Louis Smith Papers WLU.Coll.0246
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Henry Louis Smith Papers
Inclusive 1888-1951
Bulk 1912-1940
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Smith, Henry Louis
Smith, O. Norris
WLU.Coll.0246
3 Linear Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of O. Norris Smith, son of Henry Smith, in 1993.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Louis Smith was president of Davidson College from 1901-1912 and president of Washington and Lee University from 1912-1929.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of papers including letters concerning Smith's retirement from both Davidson and Washington and Lee, as well as speeches, correspondence, and articles regarding Robert E. Lee, education, modern civilization, and temperance. Also includes material regarding Smith's 1921 trip to England chairing a commission to present a copy of Houdon's statue of George Washington to the British government from the Commonwealth of Virginia.
Temperance; Prohibition; Correspondence; Monuments; England; Lee, Robert E., General (Robert Edward); Washington, George; Houdon, Jean Antoine; Washington and Lee University; Davidson College; Smith, O. Norris
- Control Folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters to him and family, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters to him and family with some answers, no date (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clippings about Accident (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Trip to Alaska, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Biographical Info, no date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Biographical Info - Clippings (most post retirement), no date (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Typescript for "Climbing Towards Success", no date (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Draft of "Climbing Towards Success", no date (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, no date (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1938-1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence and Speeches on Davidson College, 1888-1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1911-12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-01 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-01 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-01 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-01 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-02 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-02 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee, 1912-06 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Davidson to Washington and Lee Clippings, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Articles on Education, no date (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Speeches and Articles on Education, no date (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Speeches and Articles on Education, no date (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Speeches and Articles on Education, no date (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Trip to England Clippings, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Trip to England Clippings, no date (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Trip to England Clippings, no date (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Trip to England Correspondence - Photo, no date (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Trip to England - Excursion to the continent, no date (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Trip to England Memorabilia, no date (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Trip to England Memorabilia, no date (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Publications on Trip to England (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Speeches on England, no date (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Typescript for "Enriching your Vocabulary", no date (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Manuscripts for "Enriching Your Vocabulary", no date (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Notes on "Enriching Your Vocabulary", no date (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Speeches about Robert E. Lee, no date (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Equestrian Statue Presentation, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- General Lee as an Educator, no date (Box 2, Folder 43)
- The Inner Character of Robert E. Lee, no date (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Lee After Appomattox, no date (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Lee, the All-American Progressive, no date (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Lee, Builder of the New South, no date (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Lee, The Christian Educator, no date (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Lee, The Educator and His Institution, no date (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Lee, The Life Long Rebel, no date (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Lessons from the Life of Lee, no date (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Lessons from the Life of Lee (Variations), no date (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Living from the Life of Lee, no date (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Life Decisions of Robert E. Lee, no date (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Miscellaneous, no date (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Omicron Delta Kappa Ideal: Robert E. Lee, no date (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Robert E. Lee, the Christian, no date (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Victory of the Vanquished, no date (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Welcoming the British Delegation at the Tomb of Lee, no date (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Miscellany, no date (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Modern Civilization - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Modern Civilication - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Modern Civilization - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Modern Civilization - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Modern Civilization - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Modern Civilization - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Modern Civilization - Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 3, Folder 67)
- North Carolina Mallers Speeches, no date (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Peace and Militarism Speeches and Articles, no date (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Photographs, 1895-1921-02-21 (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Ring-tum Phi President's Paragraph, no date (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Smith, Frank (son), no date (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Speeches on Miscellaneous Subjects, no date (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Speeches on Miscellaneous Subjects, no date (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Speeches on Miscellaneous Subjects, no date (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Speeches on Miscellaneous Subjects, no date (Box 3, Folder 76)
- Temperance - Printed Matter, no date (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Temperance - Printed matter, no date (Box 3, Folder 78)
- Temperance - Printed Matter, no date (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Temperance - Speech and Writing, no date (Box 3, Folder 80)
- Washington and Lee - Miscellaneous Material, no date (Box 3, Folder 81)
- Washington and Lee - Retirement Correspondence, 1928-10-1928-11 (Box 3, Folder 82)
- Washington and Lee - Retirement Correspondence, 1928-12-1930-01 (Box 3, Folder 83)
- Washington and Lee - Retirement Correspondence, 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 84)
- World War I - Balloon Propaganda Project Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 3, Folder 86)
- World War I - Balloon Propaganda Project. Correspondence, 1940-1950 (Box 3, Folder 87)
- World War I - Balloon Propaganda Project. Notes by Henry Louis Smith, no date (Box 3, Folder 88)
- World War I Balloon Propaganda Project Clippings, no date (Box 3, Folder 89)